WILLIAM MAYOR

FULL-STACK WEB ENGINEER, SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR

www.williammayor.co.uk jobs@williammayor.co.uk +447500222670

Technical

Python

HTML / CSS / Javascript

Git

PostgreSQL / MySQL

Knockout.js / jQuery / Underscore.js

SASS / Bourbon / Neat

LaTeX

OS X / Linux

Heroku

Profile

I'm a code monkey at heart; I love building solutions. I am a usability enthusiast, lots of my work at Diversity and Ability focusses around making software and the web accessible and usable. I also enjoy exploring and playing with data. My MRes and MPhil research looked at distributed, peer-to-peer networks with millions of nodes, exploring that data space was a fantastic challenge. In my spare time I like to code, I also enjoy wood turning, cooking, and the occasional video game.

Experience

UCL Media Institute 2014

Software Engineer

I built a cross-collection, concept-based search engine for media assets. The beta version can be accessed here:

median.herokuapp.com.

Diversity and Ability 2009 to present Systems Administrator, Web Developer I setup, run, and maintain the Google Apps for Business provision for Diversity and Ability. I also work as their sole web developer; rebuilding their entire web ecosystem.

Freelance 2009 to present Software Engineer, Web Developer I have built many websites and software projects. Details of some can be found on my GitHub page.

MRes Dissertation 2012

Researcher

I worked on improving the reliability of the BitTorrent protocol by fully decentralising the peer discovery mechanisms. Paper published

in IEEE P2P2013.

BSc Dissertation 2011 Software Engineer I built a collaborative, real-time, cloud-based IDE using Google Wave technology.

Education

MPhil Crime and Security Science 2012 to present

University College London, UK

MRes Crime and Security Science 2011 to 2012

University College London, UK

BSc Computer Science 2008 to 2011

University College London, UK

References

Ingemar Cox Director of Research

Computer Science Department, University College London

Atif Choudhury CEO

Diversity and Ability

For privacy reasons, contact details are available on request. Public profiles are available: Ingemar, Atif